http://www.kisc.ch/privacy-policy

Be prepared for activities
VolunteerWhy volunteer at KISC?
Book
VolunteeringWhy volunteer at KISC?
You are hereHome/Privacy Policy
This “Privacy Policy” forms an integral part of the “General Terms & Conditions”, to be consulted here. All definitions and conditions provided therein are also applicable to this Privacy Policy.
Privacy statement
Kandersteg International Scout Centre considers your privacy of the utmost importance and we take due care of the security, integrity and confidentiality of your personal data.
Controller
Kandersteg International Scout Centre processes personal data of the Users in accordance with the Swiss Federal Data Protection Act (hereinafter: “DPA”) dated 19 June 1992. The controller, responsible for the processing of such data, is Kandersteg International Scout Centre, Association under Swiss law, Wagetiweg 7, CH-3718 Kandersteg, Switzerland.
Personal Data we may collect
We may collect and process the following data about you:
Information that you provide by filling in forms on our site at www.kisc.ch such as your name, phone number, email address, and postal address. This includes information provided when making a booking, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information if you report a problem with our site.
Information that you provide by applying to volunteer or work at our organisation such as name, phone number, email address, postal address passport details, medical certificate, contact details, photo and video record.
Information that you provide in order to sign up as a member of our Association, and a log of payment of membership dues.
If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
Details of your visits to our website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.
Information that you upload to our site and social media channels.
Information from your passport upon arrival.
We use cookies on our website to personlaise content and ads, provide social media features and analyse our traffic.
Information we may collect from other sources
We may collect information from publicly available sources, or from Guests and volunteers, such as contact details and basic personal information in order to determine your capacity to support Kandersteg International Scout Centre, and to send you positive communications e.g. invitations, and/or in case of emergency as “next of kin” of those providing the information. Only the minimum information necessary for the above purposes will be collected, as a legitimate interest in accordance with the Act. We will always inform you at the earliest opportunity of this processing, which is subject to your right to opt out at any time. If you have not heard from us or submitted your details, but have received any communications containing a reference to this document, you may assume that the above case applies.
Where we store your data
By giving your unambiguous and informed consent, you agree to transfer, store or process your personal data. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure services, either in a digital form protected by a password or in paper copy, behind a locked door. In both cases, your data is only accessible to members of our staff or members of our Committee and Foundation board.
The period we store data
As there is no legal obligation to retain such data,
We will retain guest data for 10 years.
We retain with adult volunteer data for 10 years.
Why and how we use your data
The personal data as defined above are processed for purposes of administration of the KISC Association, and for running our operations (accommodation, activities, catering and other services).
In addition to the statement above, we would like to further describe the use of data from a few specific groups:
Guests
We may use information held about you in order to provide you with the services available from our Association, for emergency and rescue purposes, and as further described in our General Terms and Conditions. The collection of adults and children data is necessary for the purposes of disclosure checks and safeguarding. We may use your information for marketing purposes directly related to Kandersteg International Scout Centre.
Members of the Association
We may use your information for the administration purposes of our Association, and for communicating with you any official content regarding the Association, or promotional information.
Staff members, volunteers and applicants
We may use your data for Human Resources purposes, such as recruiting, selection, insurance, visa invitation letters, emergency and rescue purposes and other administration. We may use your information in for marketing purposes directly related recruiting of volunteers to Kandersteg International Scout Centre. The collection of adult volunteers' data is necessary for the purposes of disclosure checks and safeguarding.
Disclosure of your data
We may disclose information to third parties if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements or to protect the rights, property, or safety of our Association, our customers, or others.
We may also share data with a designated data processor, for example, to process communications that are sent. In this case, the processor is bound by a contract to only act on our instructions, as well as to enact security equivalent to ours in regard to privacy. Apart from the circumstances above, we will never share your personal data with third parties without your explicit consent to do so.
The personal data as defined above are processed for purposes of administration of the KISC Association, and for running our operations (accommodation, activities, catering and other services).
For the processing of the personal data, Kandersteg International Scout Centre has entered into agreements with the following processors:
Unico Data AG 2018, Dorfmattweg 8a, CH-3110 Münsingen, Switzerland
ASSD GmbH, Hauptstr. 8b, 82008 Unterhaching (near Munich), Germany
Typeform, SL., Bac de Roda 163, 08018 Barcelona, Spain
ActivIT s.r.o., Národná 974 01, Banská Bystrica, Slovakia
Transfer of Data to Partners
We may transfer your personal data to privileged partners of Kandersteg International Scout Centre, the World Scout Bureau and or National Scout Organisations, members of the World Organisation of the Scout Movement.
Security & Confidentiality
We shall keep your personal data confidential and shall not give the personal data to any third party unless specified otherwise in this Privacy Policy. We undertake all appropriate measures to ensure an adequate level of security when storing your personal data. The processors with whom we work have policies and processes of their own which we deem appropriate.
Consent
By giving your unambiguous and informed consent, you agree with this processing. You may also opt for the use of your personal data for direct marketing purposes. Such direct marketing shall mainly consist of mailings to inform you about projects, events, news and opportunities in connection with the operations of Kandersteg International Scout Centre. You may oppose against such use for direct marketing purposes at all times. Upon receiving a direct marketing e-mail, you will also be provided with the possibility of deregistration.
Use of Image
We may use photography, videos and audio recordings as a way to promote the Centre, and its activities and opportunities. The use of the personal image will be restricted to promotional purposes of the Centre and Scouting Movement. Kandersteg International Scout Centre has ownership of any content it creates when using other people’s personal image, within the premises of this policy.
Cookies
This website uses cookies. We use cookies to personalise content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our site with our social media and analytics partners who may combine it with other information that you’ve provided to them or that they’ve collected from your use of their services. You consent to our cookies if you continue to use our website.
Cookies are small text files that can be used by websites to make a user's experience more efficient.
The right of access, correction, restriction of processing, deletion, data portability and right to object
You have the right to access your own personal data saved by Kandersteg International Scout Centre without any charge. Moreover, you have the right of correction of incorrect data, and the blocking and deletion of your personal data. Further, you have the right to data portability and the right to object.
Review and Evaluation of our Privacy
This policy will have a formal review date of two years, however; if any aspect is found to be inadequate, the Policy will be reviewed earlier.
Contact
If you have any questions relating to the processing of your personal data, your privacy rights or this Privacy Policy; or if you would like to exercise your rights by sending a letter with a copy of a legitimate piece of identification to Kandersteg International Scout Centre, Wagetiweg 7, 3718 Kandersteg, Switzerland; or by sending an e-mail to us.
About us
Plan & Stay
Support Us
Webcam from KISC
Programme
Jobs & Volunteering
News
Booking
FAQ
Media Kit
Newsletter
Contacts
Privacy Policy
General Terms & Conditions
Please note that our website is still undergoing improvements. We welcome your feedback.
Copyright ©2020 Kandersteg International Scout Centre
Our main partner is WOSM
Created by ActivIT
COVID-19: We are doing everything possible to keep the centre open to guests and safe for everyone.
See our COVID-19 FAQ for more information.
See FAQ
This website makes use of cookies to enhance browsing experience and provide additional functionality. You consent to our cookies if you continue to use this website.
Ok Privacy policy
